

# Michael Panco Frontend Web Developer micpanco.vercel.app

+639682305982 / +639776336055 micpanco@gmail.com Cainta Rizal, Philippines

A resourceful, self-motivated, talented web developer with over **13 years of working experience** in delivering web projects to a high standard. I have a proven track record of providing delightful UI design, accurate details, and effective user experience. My technical toolkit includes advanced proficiency in JavaScript and mastery of performance testing tools and techniques.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Frontend Developer**

Sept 2022 - PRESENT

Trainalta / Encora

- Developed interactive timetable for client's gym profile programs.
- Enhance the gym page user interface to make it more appealing.
- Led the successful development of the Earnportal with the latest NextJS.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

# **Fullstack Web Developer**

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022

Vokke / GetDevs

- Refactored existing applications, cutting development time by 30% while ensuring performance standings.
- Led the successful frontend development from start to finish
- Improved user experience resulting in customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

## Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2020 – Oct 2021

Property Investment Inc.

- Developed the product CRM, and introduced all the cutting-edge tools to make the project compete with product competitors.
- Integrate marketing tools to track user product engagement.
- Contribute ideas especially on UI and UX to make it more appealing for t and easy to use.

# **Senior Web Developer**

Sep 2015 - Dec 2019

**Bizme Solutions** 

- Pioneered the overall project classesa2z.com from managing the server, building the user interface, and backend creation.
- Mentored 3 junior developers in software development processes.
- Facilitated integration of third-party services like Stripe and other APIs to satisfy customer's needs.
- Communicate with the project owner to ensure the functionalities are adequately adapted.

Web Developer Software Developer Junior Web Developer Bona88 Casino Mobile Ventures Inc. PH Offshore Inc. Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Jun 2012 – Dec 2014 Jan 2010 – May 2012

#### **SKILLS & COMPETENCIES**

- React / NextJS
- React Native
- Strapi / Contentful
- MaterialUI / Tailwind / ShadCN UI
- NodeJS / ExpressJS / NestJS
- Figma Design Conversion
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Cross Browser
  Compatibility
- Algolia / Elasticsearch
- Adobe Photoshop
- GIT
- Web Performance Optimization
- Agile and Scrum
- Command Line Tools

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Teamwork
- Works well under pressure
- Willingness to try new things
- Learning agility
- Resilience
- Problem Solving
- Creativity

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2009 Navotas Polytechnic College, Navotas City, Philippines

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Gender: Male

Age: 36

Date of Birth: June 26, 1988

Civil Status: Married